{
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "An estimate based on the historical data of how often a threat would be successful in exploiting a vulnerability is known as:",
      "options": ["ALE", "SLA", "ARO", "SLE"],
      "correct_answers": ["ARO"]
    },
    {
      "question": "In the context of risk assessment, the Exposure Factor (EF) is defined as the percentage of loss that a realized threat would have on an asset. If an organization has an asset valued at $10,000 and the EF is determined to be 20%, what would be the SLE?",
      "options": ["$500", "$2,000", "$5,000", "$10,000"],
      "correct_answers": ["$2,000"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the answers listed below refers to a comprehensive document used in risk management and project management to identify, assess, and track risks?",
      "options": ["Risk register", "Risk heat map", "Risk matrix", "Risk repository"],
      "correct_answers": ["Risk register"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following terms is used to describe the specific level of risk an organization is prepared to accept in pursuit of its objectives?",
      "options": ["Risk appetite", "Risk tolerance", "Risk acceptance", "Risk capacity"],
      "correct_answers": ["Risk tolerance"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the terms listed below refers to a general term that describes an organization’s overall attitude towards risk-taking?",
      "options": ["Risk strategy", "Risk control", "Risk appetite", "Risk tolerance"],
      "correct_answers": ["Risk appetite"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Contracting out a specialized technical component when the company's employees lack the necessary skills is an example of:",
      "options": ["Risk deterrence", "Risk avoidance", "Risk acceptance", "Risk transference"],
      "correct_answers": ["Risk transference"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Cybersecurity insurance is an example of which risk management strategy?",
      "options": ["Risk avoidance", "Risk deterrence", "Risk transference", "Risk acceptance"],
      "correct_answers": ["Risk transference"]
    },
    {
      "question": "In the context of risk acceptance, choosing not to apply certain controls or safeguards for a specific risk is called:",
      "options": ["Exception", "Evasion", "Exemption", "Exclusion"],
      "correct_answers": ["Exemption"]
    },
    {
      "question": "In the risk acceptance strategy, the practice of temporarily not complying with a standard or policy due to a specific risk scenario is referred to as:",
      "options": ["Exclusion", "Exception", "Evasion", "Exemption"],
      "correct_answers": ["Exception"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Disabling certain system functions or shutting down the system when risks are identified is an example of:",
      "options": ["Risk acceptance", "Risk avoidance", "Risk transference", "Risk deterrence"],
      "correct_answers": ["Risk avoidance"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following terms describes the process of taking proactive measures to reduce the impact of identified risks?",
      "options": ["Risk acceptance", "Risk avoidance", "Risk transference", "Risk mitigation"],
      "correct_answers": ["Risk mitigation"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the acronyms listed below refers to a maximum allowable time to restore critical business functions after a disruption?",
      "options": ["SLA", "RTO", "MTTF", "RPO"],
      "correct_answers": ["RTO"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following defines the maximum acceptable amount of data loss measured by a specific point in time before a disaster or outage?",
      "options": ["RPO", "MTBF", "RTO", "MTTR"],
      "correct_answers": ["RPO"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the terms listed below is used to describe the average time required to repair a failed component or device?",
      "options": ["MTBF", "RPO", "MTTR", "SLA"],
      "correct_answers": ["MTTR"]
    },
    {
      "question": "A high MTBF value indicates that a component or system provides low reliability and is more likely to fail.",
      "options": ["True", "False"],
      "correct_answers": ["False"]
    },
    {
      "question": "A metric that represents the average amount of time a device or system is expected to operate before experiencing its first failure is known as:",
      "options": ["MTTR", "SLA", "MTBR", "MTTF"],
      "correct_answers": ["MTTF"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following answers refers to a contractual provision that grants one party the right to inspect the other party’s operations, facilities, processes, and records?",
      "options": ["Right-to-audit clause", "Oversight clause", "Compliance verification clause", "Transparency clause"],
      "correct_answers": ["Right-to-audit clause"]
    },
    {
      "question": "In the context of third-party risk assessment and management, which process involves conducting thorough investigations to verify the credentials, reliability, and integrity of potential vendors?",
      "options": ["Reference check", "Compliance review", "Due diligence", "Vendor appraisal"],
      "correct_answers": ["Due diligence"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the terms listed below refers to a situation where a party’s impartiality could be questioned due to potential personal or financial gains?",
      "options": ["Dual relationship", "Undue influence", "Conflict of interest", "Self-dealing"],
      "correct_answers": ["Conflict of interest"]
    },
    {
      "question": "An agreement between a service provider and users defining the nature, availability, quality, and scope of the service to be provided is called:",
      "options": ["SOW", "MSA", "SLA", "MOU"],
      "correct_answers": ["SLA"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following terms refers to an agreement that specifies performance requirements for a vendor?",
      "options": ["MSA", "SLA", "MOU", "SOW"],
      "correct_answers": ["SLA"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the acronyms listed below refers to a formal and often legally binding document that outlines specific responsibilities, roles, and terms agreed upon by two or more parties?",
      "options": ["SOW", "MOA", "MSA", "MOU"],
      "correct_answers": ["MOA"]
    },
    {
      "question": "A type of nonbinding agreement outlining mutual goals and the general framework for cooperation between two or more parties is referred to as:",
      "options": ["MOA", "SOW", "MOU", "MSA"],
      "correct_answers": ["MOU"]
    },
    {
      "question": "A type of legally binding contract that establishes the foundational terms and conditions governing future agreements between two parties is known as:",
      "options": ["MOU", "SLA", "MSA", "SOW"],
      "correct_answers": ["MSA"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following acronyms refers to a document that authorizes, initiates, and tracks the progress and completion of a particular job or task?",
      "options": ["SOW", "WO", "SLA", "MSA"],
      "correct_answers": ["WO"]
    }
  ]
}